Inventory of the Slavic Book Dealer Catalogs
Department of Special Collections
- Pegasus - International Booksellers, Slavic Department (Amsterdam, Holland), Oct 1985-Sept 1994; n.d. (Box 52, Folder 2)
  Contains 6 catalogs / price lists, 2 questionnaires (one completed), related correspondence (1 page). Multilingual.
- Pelikan, Wydawnictwo [The Publishing House] (Warsaw, Poland), n.d. (Box 52, Folder 3)
  Contains a press release in Polish, 1 page.
- Petropolis (Berlin), 1936-1937; n.d. (Box 52, Folder 4)
  Contains 2 catalogs and a press release. In Russian (old spelling). One catalog is damaged.
- Pilsudski Institute of America (New York), 1974; 1980; 1982-1983 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  Contains catalogs no. 8, 11(2 copies), 12 (2 copies, both annotated), and a bulletin; 6 items total. In Polish, English, French and German mostly. Some items are slightly damaged.
- The Plaza Book Auction Corp., April 1934 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  Contains a catalog, in Russian (Latin transliteration) and English mostly. Slightly damaged.
- Plotkin, Emile (Tel-Aviv, Israel), n.d. (Box 52, Folder 7)
  Contains a typewritten price list in Russian and a note attached, in English.
- Pochta Rossii [Russian Postal Service], 1999 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  Contains a catalog, in Russian mostly.
- Podunajská Knižnica Komárno (Slovenia), 2000-2001 (Box 52, Folder 9)
  Contains a catalog / price list, in Slovenian.
- Poets' and Painters' Press (London), 1988-1989; n.d. (Box 52, Folder 10)
  Contains 2 leaflets / price lists, in Polish.
- Polemika (Paris), Summer 1983 -Summer 1986; n.d. (Box 52, Folder 11)
  Contains catalogs / photocopies of catalogs / price lists, press releases, order forms, leaflets; 30 items total (including doubles). In Polish mostly.
- Poliart Beata Kalke, Antykwariat (Poland), March 1996 (Box 52, Folder 12)
  Contains a catalog and a postcard, in Polish.
- Polish Association for the Club of Rome (Warsaw, Poland), n.d. [1991?] (Box 52, Folder 13)
  Contains an informational leaflet, in Polish.
- The Polish Book Importing Co., Inc., Wanda E. Prus (New York) [1 of 2], April 1933-June 1939; 1947; 1950-1953; n.d. (Box 52, Folder 14)
  Contains catalogs and price lists, 13 items total (including doubles). In Polish, slightly damaged.
- The Polish Book Importing Co., Inc., Wanda E. Prus (New York) [2 of 2], 1928-1933; 07.06.1959-10.02.1968; 01 (Box 52, Folder 15)
  011986-08[?].03
- Polish book dealers clippings, 1973; 1985-1986; n.d. (Box 52, Folder 16)
  Contains off prints, clippings / photocopies of clippings, newspapers, tear sheets; 8 items total, in Polish.
- Polish Bookstore (NY), Winter/Spring 2000 - Winter/Spring 2001 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  Contains catalogs no. 23-25, in Polish.
- Polish Bookstore in Ottawa, 1990-1999; n.d. (Box 53, Folder 2)
  Contains catalogs / price lists, PR, order forms; 13 items total. In Polish.
- Polish Émigré Publishers and Publications, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 3)
  Contains a typewritten annotated list.
- Polish Heritage etc., March 21, 1981-Oct 1986 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  Contains newsletters, newspapers, magazines, off prints / photocopies, etc., 11 items total, in Polish.
- Polish Music - Dealers, 1994; n.d. (Box 53, Folder 5)
  Contains a catalog / price list and a photocopy of a catalog, in Polish.
- Polish Research Library - Rare Books, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 6)
  Contains a catalog / printout, in Polish and English.
- Polish Studies Center, Indiana University, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 7)
  Contains a press release.
- Polish Teachers Association in America, Inc. (Chicago), n.d. (Box 53, Folder 8)
  Contains a typewritten price list with handwritten additions. In Polish mostly.
- Polonia, Book Store and Publishers Co. (Chicago) [1 of 6], Winter 1983 - Winter 1986 (Box 53, Folder 9)
  Contains catalogs / price lists, in Polish and English mostly, and an off print in Polish. 12 items total (including doubles).
- Polonia, Book Store and Publishers Co. (Chicago) [2 of 6], Winter/Spring 1986- Fall 1987 (Box 53, Folder 10)
  Contains 5 catalogs / price lists, in Polish and English mostly (including doubles).
- Polonia, Book Store and Publishers Co. (Chicago) [3 of 6], Spring/Summer 1988 - Fall 1989 (Box 53, Folder 11)
  Contains 6 catalogs / price lists, in Polish and English mostly (including doubles).
- Polonia, Book Store and Publishers Co. (Chicago) [4 of 6], 1989 - Fall 1993 (Box 53, Folder 12)
  Contains 11 catalogs / price lists, in Polish and English mostly.
- Polonia, Book Store and Publishers Co. (Chicago) [5 of 6], Spring/Summer 1994 - Christmas 1996 (Box 53, Folder 13)
- Polonia, Book Store and Publishers Co. (Chicago) [6 of 6], Fall 1997 - Summer 1999 (Box 53, Folder 14)
- Polska Fundacja Kulturalna [Polish Cultural Foundation] (London), 1986-1988 (Box 53, Folder 15)
  Contains 2 catalogs / price lists in Polish.
- Polskie Przedsiębiorstwo Wydawnictw Kartograficznych [Polish Cartographical Publishing House] (Warsaw), 1994-1996, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 16)
  Contains catalogs / price lists, PR, business cards, related correspondence; 10 items total. In Polish, English, and Ukrainian (in Latin transliteration).
- Polskie Towarzystwo Teologiczne [Polish Theological Society] (Krakow, Poland), 1987 (Box 53, Folder 17)
  Contains a catalog in Polish with handwritten notes.
- Polyakov, Denis (Tallinn, Estonia), 07.05.2007 (Box 53, Folder 18)
  Contains a printout of an e-mail, 1 page.
- PoMost, Publishing House (Warsaw, Poland), 1991 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  Contains a leaflet in Polish.
- Possev (Frankfurt am Main, Germany), 1975-1976; 1982-1987; 1989; 1992; n.d. (Box 54, Folder 2)
  Contains catalogs and other publications, related materials, some are in Russian. 17 items total (including doubles).
- Povolozky, J., et Co. (Paris), 1929; n.d. (Box 54, Folder 3)
  Contains 2 catalogs in Russian with enclosures, both are damaged.
- Praedicta (Jerusalem), 09.06.1997 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  Contains a fax copy of a business letter, 1 page (in English, Russian, and Hebrew).
- Prasa Polska / "Polish Press" (Warsaw, Poland), 1999 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  Contains a catalog in Polish.
- Pre-war Slavic Book Dealers [1 of 15], 1908; 1921-1922; n.d. (Box 54, Folder 6)
  Contains catalogs and fragments of catalogs from the following merchants: Shibanov, P., Antiquariat (Moscow); The Publishing House "Literatura" (Berlin); Pirozhkov, M.V. (St. Petersburg); The Publishing House "Sirin" (St. Petersburg); The Publishing House "Russkaia Kniga" (Berlin); unidentified. In Russian (the old spelling), 8 items total. Damaged, fragile.
- Pre-war Slavic Book Dealers [2 of 15], 1910; 1915 [?] (Box 54, Folder 7)
  Contains catalogs and related materials from the following merchants: The Publishing Houses "Musaget", "Al'tsion" and "Skorpion" (Moscow); P.P. Soikin's Publishing House (St. Petersburg). In Russian, 4 items total. Damaged, fragile.
- Pre-war Slavic Book Dealers [3 of 15], n.d. (Box 54, Folder 8)
  Contains fragments of a catalog, severely damaged, extremely fragile, and a photocopy of these materials, 40 pages, from the following merchant: The Russian Bookstore "Moskva" [?] (Berlin, New York). In Russian (old spelling).
- Pre-war Slavic Book Dealers [4 of 15], 1909 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  Contains a catalog from the following merchant: Soloviev, N. (St. Petersburg). In Russian (old spelling). Damaged.
- Pre-war Slavic Book Dealers [5 of 15], 1929; n.d. (Box 54, Folder 10)
  Contains catalogs, fragments of catalogs, and a typewritten note, from the following merchants: Maisel, Max N. (New York); Sabo, George (Melbourne, FLA). In Russian, approximately 5 items, damaged.
- Pre-war Slavic Book Dealers [6 of 15], 1930 (Box 54, Folder 11)
  Contains 3 identical catalogs with enclosures from the following merchant: The Publishing House "Kniga dlia vsekh" (Riga, Latvia). In Russian.
- Pre-war Slavic Book Dealers [7 of 15], 1924; 1932 (Box 54, Folder 12)
  Contains 2 catalogs from the following merchant: Wydawnictwo kasy im. Mianowskiego w Warszawie (Warsaw, Poland). In Polish, damaged.
- Pre-war Slavic Book Dealers [8 of 15], 1935 (Box 54, Folder 13)
  Contains a catalog from the following merchant: Izdatel'stvo Vsesoiuznoi Akademii Arkhitektury pri TsLK SSSR (Moscow). In Russian.
- Pre-war Slavic Book Dealers [9 of 15], n.d. (Box 54, Folder 14)
  Contains a fragment of an exhibition catalog.
- Pre-war Slavic Book Dealers [10 of 15], 1922; 1932; 1939; n.d. (Box 54, Folder 15)
  Contains 5 catalogs from the following merchants: Maisel, Max N. (New York); "Rossica. Russisches Antiquariat" (Berlin); Russian Book Co. "Moskwa" (New York); Librairie "Victoire" (Paris). In Russian mostly, some catalogs are damaged.
- Pre-war Slavic Book Dealers [11 of 15], 1929;1935 (Box 54, Folder 16)
  Contains 2 catalogs from the following merchants: "Goslitizdat" (Moscow); "Gosizdat" (Moscow). In Russian, slightly damaged.
- Pre-war Slavic Book Dealers [12 of 15], 1935; n.d. (Box 54, Folder 17)
  Contains 7 catalogs from the following merchant: Akademiia nauk SSSR (Moscow); In Russian, damaged.
- Pre-war Slavic Book Dealers [13 of 15], 1887; 1915; 1934; 1937 (Box 54, Folder 18)
  Contains 4 catalogs from the following merchants: Shibanov, P. (Moscow); "Brokgauz-Efron" (St. Petersburg); "Amkniga Corporation" (New York); "Rus' ", Zaitsev, M.V. (Kharbin, China). In Russian, fragile.
- Pre-war Slavic Book Dealers [14 of 15], 1912; 1934-1935 (Box 54, Folder 19)
  Contains 2 catalogs from the following merchant: The Bookstore "A.Val'ter, Ia. Rapa and Co." (Riga, Latvia). In Russian, German and other languages.
- Pre-war Slavic Book Dealers [15 of 15], 1882; 1893; n.d. (Box 54, Folder 20)
  Contains 4 catalogs with 3 photocopies, 7 items total, from the following merchants: Bazunov, A. (Moscow); "Galician Bazar" (New York); Nikolae, M. (St. Petersburg); Erickson, W. (St. Petersburg). In Russian, Ukrainian, Polish and other languages. Catalogs are fragile, damaged.
- Prideaux Press (England), January 1980 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  Contains a catalog in Russian and English, with handwritten marks.
- Primary Source Media (Woodbridge, CT), 1998-2000 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  Contains catalogs, price lists, correspondence, 7 items total.
- Proex, Export-Import Agency (Belgrade, Yugoslavia), n.d. (Box 55, Folder 3)
  Contains a photocopy of a price list, 2 pages, with handwritten marks; in Serbo-Croatian [?].
- Progress Books (Canada), Winter 1986-1987 (Box 55, Folder 4)
- Project / "ORPAN-Export" (Poland), June 1, 1991 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  Contains a catalog / leaflet.
- Promyk, Wydawnictwo-Publishing (Philadelphia), 1986; n.d. (Box 55, Folder 6)
  Contains 5 price lists, in Polish.
- Prosveta, Publishing House (Belgrade, Yugoslavia), n.d. (Box 55, Folder 7)
  Contains a catalog and a photocopy of a typewritten letter, 1 page; in Serbo-Croatian [?] and English.
- PTvN Polish Bookstore [1 of 2], 1993-1995 (Box 55, Folder 8)
  Contains 10 catalogs (including doubles), in Polish and English.
- PTvN Polish Bookstore [2 of 2], 1991-1992; 1996; 1998 (Box 55, Folder 9)
  Contains 3 catalogs and a typewritten letter with a price list (5 pages), in Polish and English.
- Publishing House 'St. Petersburg' (New York), 1994-1995 (Box 55, Folder 10)
  Contains 3 catalogs, in Russian.
- Puls (London), 1985-1986 (Box 55, Folder 11)
  Contains a leaflet in Polish and English, with handwritten notes.
- Püski-Corvin (New York), 1989 (Box 55, Folder 12)
  Contains a catalog in Hungarian.
- Quaritch, Bernard, Ltd. [1 of 6] (London), 2002; n.d. (Box 55, Folder 13)
- Quaritch, Bernard, Ltd. [2 of 6] (London), 2003, 2004 (Box 55, Folder 14)
  Contains 3 catalogs (including doubles).
- Quaritch, Bernard, Ltd. [3 of 6] (London), 2004, 2005 (Box 55, Folder 15)
- Quaritch, Bernard, Ltd. [4 of 6] (London), 2005 (Box 55, Folder 16)
- Quaritch, Bernard, Ltd. [5 of 6] (London), 2006, 2007 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  Contains 3 catalogs.
- Quaritch, Bernard, Ltd. [6 of 6] (London), 2007, 2008 (Box 56, Folder 2)
- Quevedo, Tobias Rodgers, Rare Books and Manuscripts (London), n.d. (Box 56, Folder 3)
- R and D Books (Salisbury, N.C.), 1973-1974, 1977-1978 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  Contains 2 catalogs, multilingual, with related materials.
- Rabinovich, Alex / "Rariora" (New York), 1981-1982; 1984-1985; 1996; n.d. (Box 56, Folder 5)
  Contains correspondence and photocopies of catalogs / price lists; 8 items.
- Radio Free Europe / Radio Liberty Inc., Research Publications, n.d. [70s?] (Box 56, Folder 6)
  Contains 3 leaflets.
- Ragusan Press / Adam S. Eterovich (San Carlos, California), 1983; 1986 [?]; n.d. (Box 56, Folder 7)
  Contains 4 catalogs (including doubles).
- Rais, Kathleen - Books (Philadelphia, PA), n.d. (Box 56, Folder 8)
  Contains a typewritten catalog in Czech and English.
- Rausen Publishers and Distributors (New York), 1973 (Box 56, Folder 9)
  Contains 2 identical catalogs, 4 press releases and a typewritten letter. In Russian.
- RBC Video (New York), 1998; n.d. (Box 56, Folder 10)
  Contains 2 catalogs / price lists, in Russian.
- Readex Microprint Corporation (New York), n.d. (Box 56, Folder 11)
  Contains a leaflet with a handwritten note on the front cover.
- Sims Reed Ltd. / "Sims Reed Rare Books" (London), n.d. [2004?] (Box 56, Folder 12)
  Contains 2 catalogs (one with typewritten enclosure) and a posted envelope.
- REES [The Center for Russian and East European Studies] (University of Pittsburg, PA), n.d. (Box 56, Folder 13)
  Contains 3 leaflets and a press release with an order form.
- Regula Pragensis (Prague, Czech Republic), 1994-1995; 1997; n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1)
  Contains 5 catalogs, 2 photocopies of typewritten price lists and miscellaneous photocopies (7 pages total). In Czech mostly.
- Reklamfilm (Moscow), n.d. (Box 57, Folder 2)
  Contains 8 photos with an envelope and 6 posters. In Russian and Latvian.
- Relod Ltd. / "Triangle Plus" (Moscow), Jan 30, 1997; n.d. (Box 57, Folder 3)
  Contains a catalog and a business letter with a handwritten signature.See also: Oulassevich, Max.
- Reproniks Ltd. (Tula, Russia), 1991 [?] (Box 57, Folder 4)
  Contains a photocopy of a catalog with enclosures, in Russian.
- Rodina [Illustrated monthly magazine], Nov 15, 1994; n.d. (Box 57, Folder 5)
  Contains a business letter, a press release and a catalog; 3 pages total.
- Rodipet S.A. (Romania), 1995, 1996 (Box 57, Folder 6)
  Contains 2 catalogs and a business letter. Multilingual.
- Rospechat', Federal Agency [ 1 of 2], 1992-1993, 1996 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  Contains a photocopy of a price list and a catalog. In Russian mostly.
- Rospechat', Federal Agency [ 2 of 2], 1997, 1998 (Box 57, Folder 8)
  Contains 3 catalogs. In Russian.
- Norman Ross Publishing Inc., 1995-2000; n.d. (Box 57, Folder 9)
  Contains newsletters, correspondence, press releases, related materials; 37 items total. Some materials are in Russian.
- Rossica G.M.B.H. (Berlin), Sept 1929 (Box 57, Folder 10)
  Contains a catalog, in Russian (pre-revolutionary spelling), damaged.
- Rossiiskaia natsional'naia biblioteka [Russian National Library] (St. Petersburg), Nov 9, 1995 (Box 57, Folder 11)
- Roublev, Michel (California), March 23, 1981 (Box 57, Folder 12)
  Contains a catalog, in Russian (Latin transliteration) and English.
- Rowman and Littlefield Publishers, Inc., 1999-2000 (Box 57, Folder 13)
- Rudzki, George J. (San Diego, CA), April 5, 1988; n.d. (Box 57, Folder 14)
  Contains a typewritten price list and related correspondence, 3 items total. Multilingual.
- Russia Online, Inc. (Kensington, MD), 2008 (Box 57, Folder 15)
  Contains a newspaper and an e-mail printout, 2 pages. In Russian and English.
- Russian Academy of Sciences (Moscow), 1999 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  Contains 2 catalogs and a handwritten note. Catalogs are in Russian.
- Russian Archive Series (University of Pittsburg, PA), 90s [?]; 2002 [?]; n.d. (Box 58, Folder 2)
  Contains various typewritten catalogs, order forms with handwritten notes and marks, related documents; 5 items total. In Russian mostly.
- Russian Bibliographical Society, 02.26.1993 (Box 58, Folder 3)
  Contains an e-mail printout / price list with numerous handwritten notes.
- Russian Book / Alexander L. Umansky (New York), July 1, 1996 (Box 58, Folder 4)
- Russian Book Chamber (Moscow), 1996 (Box 58, Folder 5)
  Contains 2 catalogs in Russian.
- Russian Booksellers in America, 1935 [?]; 1957; n.d. (Box 58, Folder 6)
  Contains off prints of articles related to Russian booksellers in America and Europe, 15 pages total. In Russian.
- Russian Center (Fordham University, New York), n.d. (Box 58, Folder 7)
  Contains a price list, 1 page.
- Russian Entertainment and Wholesale Inc. (New York), Fall 2003 (Box 58, Folder 8)
- Russian House Ltd. (New York), 1992-1996 (Box 58, Folder 9)
  Contains 12 catalogs (including doubles), in Russian and English.
- Russian Information and Business Center, Inc. (Washington), n.d. (Box 58, Folder 10)
  Contains 2 catalogs and related documents, 8 items total.
- Russian Information Services, Inc., 1994-1995 (Box 58, Folder 11)
  Contains 4 catalogs (including doubles) and a leaflet.
- Russian Language Specialties (Michigan), 1973; 1985; 1988; 1989; 1994; n.d. (Box 58, Folder 12)
  Contains a catalog, typewritten price lists, a calendar; 8 items total (including doubles). Multilingual.
- Russian Library in Rome, Sept 29-Oct 29, 1984 (Box 58, Folder 13)
  Contains a photocopy [?] of a typewritten letter and a photocopy of a clipping. In Russian.
- Russian Mouse Ltd. (New York), Autumn 1999 (Box 58, Folder 14)
- Russian National Bibliography / "MIR Dialogue" and the Russian Book Chamber (Box 58, Folder 15)
  Contains a leaflet in English and an e-mail printout (in Russian, Latin transliteration).
- Russian Orthodox Youth Committee, Inc. (New York), 1993; 1998 (Box 58, Folder 16)
  Contains a catalog in Russian (old spelling) and a business card in English (Mrs. Irene Dutikow).
- Russian Press Service, Inc. (Evanston, IL) [1 of 6], June-August 1992, June 1993, March-May 1994 (Box 58, Folder 17)
  Contains typewritten press releases and price lists, 7 items total. Some materials are in Russian (Latin transliteration).
- Russian Press Service, Inc. (Evanston, IL) [2 of 6], 1995 (Box 58, Folder 18)
  Contains 3 typewritten price lists / catalogs. Multilingual.
- Russian Press Service, Inc. (Evanston, IL) [3 of 6], 1996-1997 (Box 59, Folder 1)
  Contains 10 catalogs, some with handwritten notes / marks and / or notes attached. Mostly in Russian (Latin transliteration).
- Russian Press Service, Inc. (Evanston, IL) [4 of 6], 1998-1999 (Box 59, Folder 2)
  Contains catalogs, releases and related materials, 8 items total. Mostly in Russian (Latin transliteration).
- Russian Press Service, Inc. (Evanston, IL) [5 of 6], 2000-2002, 2004 (Box 59, Folder 3)
  Contains catalogs, releases and related materials, 7 items total. Multilingual.
- Russian Press Service, Inc. (Evanston, IL) [6 of 6], 2005, 2008 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  Contains 2 catalogs and a business letter, 1 page. Multilingual.
- Russian State University of Humanities (Moscow), 1997 (Box 59, Folder 5)
- Russian Statistical Yearbook (Moscow), 1996 (Box 59, Folder 6)
  Contains a catalog of publications and information services.
- Russian Studies Publications / "Harwood Academic Publishers" (Medford, MA), 2005; n.d. (Box 59, Folder 7)
  Contains a catalog and a printout of a catalog, 33 pages.
- Russian World (Brooklyn, NY), 1998, 1999 (Box 59, Folder 8)
- Russian-Baltic Information Center - Blitz (San Rafael, CA - Saint-Petersburg), 1994-1997 (Box 59, Folder 9)
  Contains catalogs / price lists, releases, photocopies, notes etc., 21 items total. Some with handmade notes / marks and / or damaged. In English and Russian.
- Russica / Kaplanski, Boris (Paris), 1972-1973; n.d. (Box 59, Folder 10)
- Russica Book Shop / "Russica Book and Art Shop, Inc." (New York) [1 of 17], n.d. (Box 59, Folder 11)
  Contains book lists (printed, computer printouts, photocopies), releases, leaflets; 13 items total. In English and Russian (both in Cyrillic and Latin transliteration). Names: Valery Kuharets.
- Russica Book Shop / "Russica Book and Art Shop, Inc." (New York) [2 of 17], n.d. (Box 59, Folder 12)
  Contains releases, leaflets, postcards, stationery, related materials; 25 items total (including doubles). In English and Russian (both in Cyrillic and Latin transliteration). Names: Valery Kuharets.
- Russica Book Shop / "Russica Book and Art Shop, Inc." (New York) [3 of 17], n.d. (Box 59, Folder 13)
  Contains releases and correspondence; 5 items total. In English and Russian (both in Cyrillic and Latin transliteration). Names: Valery Kuharets.
- Russica Book Shop / "Russica Book and Art Shop, Inc." (New York) [4 of 17], n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1)
  Contains book lists (printed, computer printouts, photocopies), leaflets, related documents, most with numerous handwritten notes; 9 items total. In English and Russian (both in Cyrillic and Latin transliteration). Names: Valery Kuharets.
- Russica Book Shop / "Russica Book and Art Shop, Inc." (New York) [5 of 17], 1978-1984 (Box 60, Folder 2)
  Contains book lists (printed, computer printouts, photocopies) with handwritten notes and marks, leaflets, correspondence; 15 items total. In English and Russian (both in Cyrillic and Latin transliteration). Names: Valery Kuharets.
- Russica Book Shop / "Russica Book and Art Shop, Inc." (New York) [6 of 17], 1985 (Box 60, Folder 3)
  Contains book lists (printed, computer printouts, photocopies), typewritten and handwritten correspondence, a business card, related documents; 21 items total. In English and Russian (both in Cyrillic and Latin transliteration). Names: Valery Kuharets.
- Russica Book Shop / "Russica Book and Art Shop, Inc." (New York) [7 of 17], 1986-1988 (Box 60, Folder 4)
  Contains book lists (printed, computer printouts, photocopies), leaflets, correspondence; 6 items total. In English and Russian (both in Cyrillic and Latin transliteration). Names: Valery Kuharets.
- Russica Book Shop / "Russica Book and Art Shop, Inc." (New York) [8 of 17], 1976-1978 (Box 60, Folder 5)
  Contains catalogs and typewritten price lists no. 5,8,11-12, 14-18, related materials, some heavily annotated; 10 items total. In English and Russian (both in Cyrillic and Latin transliteration). Names: Valery Kuharets.
- Russica Book Shop / "Russica Book and Art Shop, Inc." (New York) [9 of 17], 1978-1979 (Box 60, Folder 6)
  Contains catalogs and typewritten price lists no. 20-21,23-26,28-29 and one unnumbered catalog; 8 items total, some with handwritten notes and marks. In English and Russian (both in Cyrillic and Latin transliteration). Names: Valery Kuharets.
- Russica Book Shop / "Russica Book and Art Shop, Inc." (New York) [10 of 17], 1979 (Box 60, Folder 7)
  Contains catalogs and typewritten price lists no. 29 (reprint) and 30, both with handwritten notes and marks. In English and Russian (both in Cyrillic and Latin transliteration). Names: Valery Kuharets.
- Russica Book Shop / "Russica Book and Art Shop, Inc." (New York) [11 of 17], 1980 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  Contains catalogs and typewritten price lists no. 31,33-34,37,39-40, some with handwritten notes and marks. In English and Russian (both in Cyrillic and Latin transliteration). Names: Valery Kuharets.
- Russica Book Shop / "Russica Book and Art Shop, Inc." (New York) [12 of 17], 1980 (Box 61, Folder 2)
  Contains catalogs and typewritten price lists no. 42-43,45-46,48; 6 items total (including doubles), some with handwritten notes and marks. In English and Russian (both in Cyrillic and Latin transliteration). Names: Valery Kuharets.
- Russica Book Shop / "Russica Book and Art Shop, Inc." (New York) [13 of 17], 1981 [?] (Box 61, Folder 3)
  Contains catalogs and typewritten price lists no. 53-56,59,64-68; 12 items total (including doubles), some with handwritten notes and marks. In English and Russian (both in Cyrillic and Latin transliteration). Names: Valery Kuharets.